Some things never let us go.
The Little Things is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by John Lee Hancock.
Deputy Sheriff Joe "Deke" Deacon joins forces with Sgt.
Jim Baxter to search for a serial killer who's terrorizing Los Angeles.
As they track the culprit, Baxter is unaware that the investigation is dredging up echoes of
Deke's past, uncovering disturbing secrets that could threaten more than his case.
Joe 'Deke' Deacon, played by Denzel Washington.
Jim Baxter, played by Rami Malek.
Albert Sparma, played by Jared Leto.
Detective Sal Rizoli, played by Chris Bauer.
Flo Dunigan, played by Michael Hyatt.
LASD Captain Carl Farris, played by Terry Kinney.
The Little Things is a 2021 American neo-noir psychological crime thriller film directed,
written, and co-produced by John Lee Hancock and co-produced by Mark Johnson.
Set in early 1990s Los Angeles, the film follows two detectives (Denzel Washington and Rami Malek) who
investigate a string of murders, which lead them to a strange loner who may be the culprit (Jared Leto).
The film initially began development in 1993, when Hancock wrote the original draft of the screenplay,
with various names attached to direct or act, but it languished in development hell.
The project was revitalized in 2019, with announcements that Hancock would direct,
with Malek, Leto and Washington to portray the main characters.
Principal photography began in Los Angeles on September
2, 2019, and wrapped in December 2019.
The Little Things was released in the United States
on January 29, 2021, by Warner Bros.
Pictures, both theatrically and, for one month,
simultaneously on the HBO Max streaming service.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the cast but criticism of the
screenplay, and grossed $30.8 million worldwide against its $30 million production budget.
For his performance, Leto received Golden Globe and SAG
nominations for Best Supporting Actor.
The film explores themes of detective, deputy
sheriff, cop, serial killer, crime scene.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.